When the world first went to war, they were the first to fly.
Flyboys is a action, adventure, drama film directed by Tony Bill.
The adventures of the Lafayette Escadrille, young Americans who
volunteered for the French military before the U.S.
entered World War I, and became the country's first fighter pilots.
Blaine Rawlings, played by James Franco.
Eddie Beagle, played by David Ellison.
Capt. Thenault, played by Jean Reno.
William Jensen, played by Philip Winchester.
Mr. Jensen, played by Todd Boyce.
Sheriff Detweiller, played by Mac McDonald.
Flyboys is a 2006 war drama film starring James Franco, Martin
Henderson, David Ellison, Jennifer Decker, Jean Reno.
It was directed by Tony Bill, a pilot and aviation
enthusiast, and written by Phil Sears, Blake T.
Evans, and David S.
Set during World War I, the film follows the enlistment, training, and combat experiences of a group of young Americans who
volunteered to become fighter pilots in the Lafayette Escadrille, the 124th air squadron formed by the French in 1916.
Flyboys was released on September 22, 2006 by MGM.
It received mixed reviews from critics, who criticized the
performances, screenplay and visual effects.
It was also a box-office bomb, grossing $18
million against its $60 million budget.
The film explores themes of world war i, fighter
pilot, based on true story, biplane.
The tone is emotional.